# Christopher Peterjeyaraj

Chrispeterjeyaraj | in christopherpeterjeyaraj✓ chrispeterjeyaraj@gmail.com | +91-9940582097

## SUMMARY

As a seasoned Full Stack Developer with 13+ years of experience, I've honed my skills in crafting professional-grade web and mobile applications. I bring a proven track record of successfully designing, developing, and deploying applications. With a deep understanding of the latest technologies and a knack for problem-solving, I'm ready to take on new challenges and continue to add value to organizations.

## WORK EXPERIENCE

#### HCL Technologies, Technical Specialist

Nov 2016 - present

- Currently working as an engineer on the Cisco Intersight project, where I serve as a Technical Lead on the UI Team.
- As a member of the UI team, I collaborate with the rest of the team to implement a solid and consistent User Interface using WebComponents.

#### Tychons LLC, Manager Information Technology

Jun 2013 - Nov 2016

- Worked as a Technical Manager, leading multiple ecommerce web and mobile projects for customers to transition their businesses online.
- Converted legacy product catalogs into public endpoints and integrated them with existing warehouse systems

#### RSalesArm, Web and Mobile Application Developer

May 2012 - May 2013

- Developed anytime-available (online and offline) hybrid mobile applications for CRM applications.
- Engineered middlewares to efficiently expose CRM endpoints and access secured information.
- Advocated for the mobile apps to users, provided training, and offered Long-Term Support (LTS).

#### Innospire Systems, Software Developer

May 2010 - May 2012

- Worked on rich internet applications using Microsoft Silverlight.
- Developed hybrid mobile applications to support the developed web applications.

#### EDUCATION

2006 - 2010 B.Tech at Anna University

(Percentage: 78)

### SKILLS

FrontEnd HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, React, NextJS, WebComponents, MicroFrontends,

Google Polymer, LitHtml, Redux, OpenComponents, Module Federation, MERN,

EXTJS(Sencha)

Mobile React Native, Flutter, Cordova Backend GoLang, Python, NodeJS

Containerization Docker, Kubernetes

DatabasesMongoDB, PostgreSql, MySqlSource ControlGithub, Bitbucket, SVN, GitLab